

Highlights

Product Designer - Skilled web designer/developer with over 15 years of professional experience.

Proven record of completing bold, clean, and effective designs with consistent performance ahead of schedule and under budget.

Successful product designer able to integrate both technical and creative skills to create cross-browser and cross-platform solutions with modern web architecture and navigation systems.

Experienced in many industries, including semiconductor, hospitality, entertainment, health, publishing, finance, insurance, construction, computer software, and Internet.

Proficiency

Responsive Design, CSS3, graceful degradation, Jquery, modern grid layouts, object oriented CSS, Wordpress and other CMS including TeamSite, HTML emails, analytics, SEO, user interface design, information architecture, web navigation, icon creation, web graphics, cross-platform and cross-browser issues, web template creation & content management system integrations.

Professional level expertise with Adobe Creative Suite. Comfortable in both ASP and PHP environments as well as most major javascript libraries.

I prefer WordPress, PHP, jQuery and Macs.

Education

- Cal State University Fullerton
 Web Design and Development Degree
- Coastline Community College
 Quality Assurance Degree
- Golden West College
 Business Management
- Huntington Beach High School High School Diploma

Professional Experience

Todd Lambert Enterprises, 1999 - Present

Sole Proprietor / Photographer

Conducted all facets of web development business including meeting with clients, selling web services, and developing methods for improved customer support.

I also like to travel and photograph spooky and abandoned places, at night, all by myself and all over the country. Be sure to check out my website: toddtravels.com

Primal Health, 2013 - 2014

Creative Director / Associate Developer

Responsible for all graphic components and direct marketing efforts. Worked with various departments to advance reach through social marketing, engineering and analytics. Also performed SEO and conducted extensive AB testing.

Texas Instruments, 2010 - 2013

Style Architect / Front End Developer / Senior UI Designer

Worked on all aspects of TI's website, from new ad campaigns and interactive widgets to the core infrastructure including a new redesign and replacement of site navigation site-wide. Championed responsive design techniques and other modern architecture for use on corporate site. Utilized Jquery animation for replacing all of TI's legacy Flash files.

AGJ Systems & Networks, 2008 - 2010

Web Director / Lead Developer / Senior Designer

Solely responsible for all design and development aspects of web department. Interacted with customers and other departments to integrate designs into modern, full-featured websites catered to customer needs.

TeleVox Software, 2004 - 2007

Director of Web Development

Responsible for site architecture, design, graphics, programming, copywriting/editing, project management of all TeleVox websites and online marketing campaigns. Supervised 25 designers and developers.